Halo friends.
You having a nice time and build.
Two o'clock is apparently little early for developers to wake-up I apologize we got...the crack of
noon what...net for linux give a visual studio code in there that's,
yeah, that's...it since I know the people who are watching on the web or more excited than you
all but that's fine we don't need your pity applies that's how
...hundred my boss and myself sky handsome that's how we role so
later on when we give you are dog eyes and say we're sad because you didn't
applaud we don't want your pity applause we only want when it comes from the heart.
Not... please stop moi what do you
...yourself my god is wrong with you
aren imc enhancement this is my bosco under we are the lesser scott's.
When notice were not wearing a red shirt he's actually...he's red green...he has no idea
...and we also have chinese guy who we brought to watch over us and so?
In...trust.
So, we're going to talk about as
...apps service architecture and we're really happy that you all came to hear about this with us now I want
to make sure actually switch and just show...disclaimer there
...you understand what you're seeing here today which
...by the way where we are here let's ...sorry sir?
Okay, what you're seeing here are preview bits?
And, we are not saying that just because we're afraid it's going to break
...saying that because it's literally preview bits we want to show you folks what is being
built and how it's being built and we're going to go a little bit slower because you know-how they do these things
in the keynote they give me fifteen minutes and then right before I get on stage they
go love everything that you're doing all those features are great you've got ten minutes?
And, make sure you hit the story now this is our opportunity really share with you what's going on in as
your...as...service in a full sixty-minutes so we're going to drop down
...the low-level and put it all into context google...lower bench-press you said
...preview bits which means if you try to replicate we showing today it might blow up on your
...the...live...not faking anything nothing
...fake nothing in the keynote was fake but I'm really happy that it worked great
All right so that said let's talk about it and then make sure of
course that you find...for that you are code and.
And,...we...quicken...you just keep clicking around what was that when you just skip I needed that's
...those evaluations language right after
...slide that was...because we're innovating were done this is so professional.
Ok, in as your today there
was asher websites that's where you see like get deployment that
...service...you may have seen that that's the thing that manages get
...as your websites is scaleable elastic
websites where you don't have to think about the underlying virtual machine that exist today we love that
...passage tuition everything's manage for you ...there and we may...for
...platform as a service mobile services
letting you have access to restful apis talk to things like
...talk to native apps talk to windows store apps that exist
today that's great...services reliable.
Orchestration of business processes that exist today what asher
apps services is a collection of things that you already know-how
to use today plus a couple of new things and that
is then dotted line around it that is app service.
...going to talk about the new stuff primarily for...you just said is those things don't exist anymore.
...physically exist though you have web...features
...all...so if you...you look
for those mobile services now mobile app website size web app right.
So, there are all of these things into integrated offering and what's nice about it
too is that the pricing is pretty much the same as before these things are running
a very specific when we're going to talk about the actually cheaper than it was before so we took we took all those features
...websitesafter mobile service rice talk services
...into one feature under one-price...added a few more things as well right so you already have
a website...a web app and you can do all these things and add to your at your applications you
already have today and the interesting bits that we're going to talk about primarily
are api apps and logic apps and api absence you connect
all these different things there are third-party apps there are first party after
apps and we create there's twitter connectors and dynamic connectors and sales force and
...sixty-five as well as whatever you come up with and the ability if you do in the future
very soon put those in a marketplace and that's because we know that people are building apps to talk...services today we want to
make it very easy for you take existing...throughout the day and start connecting...services riots
...feature the platform so let's get through this and get into some interesting stuff because we want
to make sure that you understand the pitch and then we'll show you the
details so web apps these the...you understand are you may in the past of thought that web
app just run node and dot net they also now run java.
They run php
...run python and there's also a new thing called the http platform connector we've
got I got...of sharpen suave running a couple of days ago we've got goal
running you can pretty much do whatever you want and the nice thing is that it's and underlying
hidden virtual machine so it's platform as a service I don't have to think about scale
...handling web jobs continues integration all those features exist
...getting better and as we talk about apps service today each of these capabilities works for each of the
...we're going to talk about...observers with my building and api
...logic app mobile app all these same capabilities are sitting
behind the scenesrunning these things right now when we talk about platform
as a service we stress how important is that you don't have to worry about the
underlying virtual machine but as with all magic layers of abstraction if,
you know, one layer below you are more powerful so
while you can choose to pretend that there isn't an actual machine running under there is and
we're going to show you why that's important and why that can make you actually
a better developer now mobile apps we've used before
we seen those some great demos from josh twist we've got the capabilities of
web jobs running for mobile apps otto load balance auto
scale all of the disaster recovery and geographic scale for mobile apps all exists
libraries we always...that we should for web apps on alta mobile
...to mobile apps yes so there...not question like what's one form what's the other
four you get the features and all of them and if you may play with mobile
left before you might have had this question like do I build a web app input apis in it
...mobile app what do I choose another goal about services
...say now you don't have to worry about if you start
...and you want to add the mobile capabilities that now is just going
in adding some things to your existing web app
...converted to a mobile lab so that's a big...of this as well as you don't have to
have this choice and make the wrong one you feel like you're stuck now you...start with
...and you can always move...mobile you can always moved api?
Now web jobs exists in web a web apps and
in mobile apps and people did some real...which the next slide people did some
...scheduling of jobs in the background like my blood sugar
automatic machine thing is actually running in a web app some pulling that information and publishing
...often to node but, that's not really a automated business process that's just the thing that runs
as a reliable job in the background what logic apps does it takes those
connectors in the ability to talk to apis and puts it into a reliable
orchestrated will workflow reliable business workflow that can scale the same way or other
apps scale and that's what I showed...showed that visual designer we're going to show the
internals at that and what we can do with that why that's important and your web apps get that now
your mobile apps can do this you can make logic apps now and you...pretty cool stuff with logic...logics apps is hey
I've got some data database and when you...put in I want to run an action
goes and grab that data...it somewhere else and we'll show some of these flows...that's the idea is you
...these workflows is actually a workload and there's a workflow in the cloud and the thing that's
so important about logic apps is that don't look at those or see talking people
talking about logic apps and think that they're trying to keep me from writing code we want you to write code with the single
responsibility principle and little services that do one specific thing and do it well and
then we're going to give you tools to go and put them together into recipes that are going to be more interesting...also
...a lot of this docket abilities
...yet behind we actually...slide on that in fact we'll talk about
than just a moment so these api apps there are dozens and dozens
...ones and I'm going to show twitter and drop box and julio and all that kind of
stuff but we want you all to make these as well and put them in the great
thing also about api apps is that...using open standards the example we're going to show you is using great
open-source library called swashbuckling and talk about swagger and what that expert that means
with the metadata means?
...piles of them the next slide shows a whole list and...actually a lot more we have more than
this was a list we did a few weeks ago so there's more than the several dozen as I recall there's like fifty
...now, yeah, okay, so, thatall wrapped up
...next slide is app service ok so let's.
Look, at it this way now you see that picture...
that window pane words like here's just for boxes and this is a tough thing about explaining architecture
payers for boxes does not make total sense.
So, I rearrange that with his permission and by the way you seen...
I put api apps...this is confusing because there's the physical reality that will
explained you about how these things live but the idea is that everything is
an api they can be should consume from
everywhere and we start talking about authorization authentication then things get really,
really exciting but this is a more kind-of and architects view of what's going on so if
we took an example like...car dealership or something like that...hit the next slide
...we expand that out this is similar to the slide this on
...briefly you might have some web sites multiple website
summary internal summer external some may be using hybrid connections some maybe using vp and doesn't
matter you've got some mobile apps windows store windows phone
whatever they're going to talk to a series of api apps and communicate
with those and then business processes that
maybe change often or need to be really reliable the kinds of things you would do invest art will
live as logic apps so maybe you can speak to what's changed with based on the next slide?
Well, actually I...exchange...this is the next evolution evolving rather
...evolving this talk so this is your best talk today those product will continue
exist like they do today we've already moved this talk to the cloud as part of
this talk services and then as part of as...after mrs we're taking all those
biztalk services features we added that we remove the cloud and now
making even more accessible to people using logic apps and that's where the real goals to
make...talk features accessible to more and more people and,
we're going to start often show that is...second actually.
...api...which is the underpinning of everything we have here so there's a couple of things that...today if
you're billion api there's a lot of things like how do you control who can
call your api what's the access control so we'll show today that
bit api apps make that very simple to do whether you just want to make it
public or private what you want to put it behind active directory of
twitter microsoft facebook or other things you can do that another thing is if you building
and api you might want to single sign on where I sign on one-time
to active directory and then as I call other apis I want...to flow through to those
...I might I might...index...and have an api at the talks to
...sixty-five and not have to be that oslo so we'll do that awful for
you another thing is metadata so one of the things that makes it an api app
it's just...so that you don't have to actually do anything special or using special
libraries you can take any api that you have the
day whether it be dot net node php python?
Java and all you to do is give us some meta
data and without metadata we can actually light up so you can easily call it from the web apps the logic apps
and everything else and we're going to go in some details on that so let's do that let's get down into the actual nitty-gritty of
it so let's switch over to eight-eighty okay.
I'm sitting here on file new project and I'm I can pick
this new option as...okay I could do that if you don't mind I
would not do that don't have to do that so I want to show...existing...api
so the api...we have there is just if you want to start off...averaging pre done for you but as
...saying earlier you can take any existing api you have...converted
into api app and we're going to work that logic and workflow right now so let's say that I've got
an existing web api and I'm
just going to change this one here this is.
A nonsense values controller all make it contacts.
we'll have it return a contact that is a thing that doesn't exist yet
and we'll go and make a new contact I'm actually going to steal from an existing.
To save time because I don't think people...I can type.
I don't know never actually seen...type.
And, here we've got to get in...getby id what I'm going to do I
have to do this for test application this is really great.
Of open-source application it's called auto
pogo automatically and make a plain old clr object and
auto pogo will go and generate basically objects...
grab that from new get bring that down.
And, then.
I'm going to borrow.
This whole chunk here.
So, the main thing that sketching...wants to...doesn't have...and way...not
...so once randomly create like fifty customers that he can actually call and use
of this answers right so here we're just going to say
...the purposes of this demo go and make me fifty people and
then basically mix-up their names jimmy's first name this and last name that and,
... randomized so this is just giving me a nice list it's like a fake database it's good for testing
really great little library and thendown here in
get we're going to return contact instead.
And, then I'm going-to go ahead and just return that users
list ok so if I go and do that?
Let's see if that works.
Thank you so there is a xml and if I put in except jason that
would come back is jason's...brought you some real data that is acheap web service
...but with these kinds of things and.
If I was going to do this as jason there's no schema here right we remember there was
the time of whizzed all the time of xml schema and they were good things
and bad things about that I lived through those times they built a lot of great stuff with those times but now
we're going more towards a more dynamic model and a more restful model and
things have changed but there is a thing called swagger.
That I can bring in my applications swagger is kind of like
wisdom
for curly braces is if that's not an unreasonable thing to say and there
is another open-source project that we use and appreciate that's called swashbuckling.
And, I'm just going to go and add that.
And, swashbuckling...going to go and add that and then run my app again and
...describe the api the role exactly I'm...go and hit slashed swagger.
I'm going to get this lovely.
And, it look it shows.
That api...one-click around...formula pace.
So, there's the get click on the get...the model of that
so this is describing the schema of this restful web service and this is not of
microsoft thing this is just an internet thing and you may have seen that kind of
thinking in a lot of the stuff that microsoft's doing if the internet did something great and will adopt that really
great thing rather than trying to invent something so this is a model allows you to do that now he go ahead
and try it out and she's got response content type application jason's
...little tester as well which is quite nice?
You can create node apps go apps whatever if they return swagger than they have
a described metadata endpoint and then we can go and do stuff with
that this actually gives you a...actually try your apis out live?
...there's a response body...that response body came back as
jason because the request said I don't want xml I want
...I could have removed the xml as with any asp
net web api removing that format or I could have it return other things as well.
So, you theoretically could go and lads langer going...the
...show the actual swaggering yeah, that's a good point thank you sir.
That was a very managerial thing for you to...mostly done.
He says...show the actual stuff.
So, this is saying that, you know,
there's an operation and this operation is called account...whatever close that one up...the
...accounts of this where api has
one for user management as well account log out blah-blah-blah change
password set password.
...any I've got jason view here to
...contacts so there's contacts get notice it says well I
also produce xml and I have these responses it provides a lot of information about
that maybe even more semantic meaning
then whittle did so rather than looking at this like I did which was ...was
...over again wow okay I think about this as a refinement of the stuff that worked in
with all the stuff that didn't work and bringing it into a model where there's a lot of
really great services out there look at it...a definition of the contact us has got a first name a last name
a birthday heights showing the types right...so
this is that right there is really significant because there's always this.
...mismatch between
the sterilization and visualization these kinds of object I spent a lot of time in the early
two thousands serialized in the serialized and stuff well one of the most requested features we've always had for
...web api was how do you do the same thing you can do with as a...which is how do I build a
...client can talk to it so we should probably do that we should okay that's.
So, the swashbuckling...showed anybody can use any a
cannot application today you can basically grab that you get package stick it into any existing
...web api project you have...generate the swagger for-you and
it will also give you that test panel you can actually try your apis and, run them.
I can go like this you
have to tell if I'm doing this right if I go and say add
app client that work with my local applications we should so I just
said ad and I can say add as...api app client.
...along the way you look...if you have...swagger file...which I will go into.
Let's watch me login.
Now I don't actually ever use this device.
Not really seriously true I don't really, really don't.
I think you're going to logins...now I don't think so I refuse notice
...refuse like six times...we want to lawyer so that's actually a...and.
No, we don't ever have bugs what that is...I
...a member of seven different individual
...subscriptions and I don't really feel like logging in the each one individually so,
then it's sensed my fear.
Don't like that all right
so I'm going to take this file here and I'm going to go and saved this jason?
Super swagger.
Dot jason.
And, then over here I can go and pointed as an apps...pointed an app service
and then this is a list of the api services rather pardon me you better
...apis man well, yeah, so, dimension I was in a lot of stuff, yeah,
we...got red-alert code apparently and I want to go ahead and grab that one.
And, this is going to go end-user thing called
auto rest that is an open-source and lovely a
thing that I give you more details on and where did end up putting that mas down here it
...folder free you put in the same of the namespaces...the names of your so, there's
...contact...overnight and actually made a mistake as...did in the web app?
No, one said anything though which makes me
disappointed frankly in this audience and their ability to keep up.
Is it is...so scary unfortunately
...wants...to the api in the outages own api?
So,...api in api the colonizing to create a...editor all myself.
Crap I there was a memo...stop doing that in public.
...you...that...
I think that the subject of the...was unprofessional.
What is significant?
Anyone hiring anyone hiring.
You know, scott I have kids...
We have little kids so this is going and this is what's great about this too is
there's no black boxes okay there's nothing hidden here because sometimes when you hide
...behind a dialog box and then you only...see what's happening...
what did you just do this is generated code generate with
...open-source project...you can go and look at you can modify the generate code you
can modify the generators you can write your own custom generators
...makes you happy and this is just doing a restful call...bringing this data backed
away we understand it this is actually the same technology used to the accuracy case so part of our team
...the...and we have this problem years ago it's like how do you build measure sdk for dot
net and for java and for javascript
...for php...for python for ruby we don't want to build that same sdk a million
times so we actually inside microsoft have swagger files that define the as
your api service we run this exact same tool over those
swagger files to generate what we call the accuracy...so think about that
per second, you know, how we go and we show you the cross-platform address dk
...written the note and...I always point out how and we're calling back and restful api that
edgerton somebody some brilliant person internally said hey this is cool we should give this to the
people...and we did and that's useful and that's
...kind of transparency and kind of interaction
...makes me happy and this is doing that boring code the boiler plate code,
you know, go...credentials if they're there and get a response and traced
...service reference back to acinet
...what api...a great point so it's kind of like
...service reference except the service reference is a restful aps which is really,
really nice now in this instance here as I recall boss you agree to web
...eight or whatever you called...thingI'm going to go and say var?
Applications six because that's what you would call your api.
Dots web is incentivizing new it up...
...your clients and then.
...like that.
Right...contacts called gets on context.
Called dot get...those are extension methods all of that not hidden.
Now this though needs the url though isn't it does because I haven't put it in
asher yet so that's an override so I'm going to go and say like this
candles can I just go into like that you can.
...a new...some nonsense.
Now we go if you
...one of these from as your we actually put the uri and for-you automatically so when
...showing the one running...your...all right so I put a break point there.
Fifty people often.
Moi gets better.
But, wait that's not all.
Which was better which...thinking I was thinking of showing the command-line okay...let's
do it so...as we mentioned while...working on the computer we
mention that this is the same tool that we used to build the accuracy case that we're running
out of the covers we
do so not only can tool generate the csharp that's got to showed but,
I think we got to build this morning of this that will actually let us do I python java
...said it's almost ok so, we just got a
...like last night of some stuff is going to go up on
...get have soon this is preview but the intent is to make it so
any language that makes you happy you can go and generate these things are...that a...here I want to make the
point anything you like on the server can make these apis
and anything you want to consume them with so it is nondenominational, yeah, but,
...that guy I think of now you can
...api in acinet...and you can say hey...need if you can you
clients to anybody that wants to call your apis...php if you need python right
will have ios android in the future as well and, with...means you can package them up it makes you happy you don't have to
make your customers run this stuff you could generated...the way you want to look documented
at anything that you want to document stuff and when they see that swagger file they're going to have
...and there are other open-source projects
that will help you build the documentation for your web apis and take that information and make it available
people so you now get basically client asti
case for anything you do but also,
you know, as we said before this api we could...node or phd we generate this so,
yeah, so, right here I just showed you what's inside of that command file
...auto rest which is the...tool...in this case
...a pet store and then it's going to say ...decode generator is
node in this example that code generator is actually a dot net type
there's an auto rest dot jason file inside of which
one can express other things so let's take a look at this real quick?
And, then we'll run and look at the results
...so the code generators are extensible now this is
lock-down.
Additionally the modeler czar as well so that brings up some interesting things for the future so let's look at java
okay and then I'm going to use code.
And, let's take a look at.
Generated csharp.
Job up there you go.
And, then within this.
You've got a client app and in some of the instances there are dependencies so,
for example, you can see that this is bringing in microsoft as your filter
...service...can have things like, you know,
page paging and get by this and get by...every instances different and
...employee every implementation is custom so, for example,
if I use the...rest node this is really important
is generated code requires this runtime and
pm package so...I would include that into my packages jason and go and run
and pm install and that's going to support that...the code for node.
That's why this there is your being a
...boiler plate kind of boring pipeline type stuff.
And, then.
There's a...
...and does all...doing it
...really nice clean idiomatic in this case javascript
idiomatic whatever makes you happy with...to look write the language...so right and that is the intent in
every instance so they were kind enough to give us this in java in
csharp and then also this was when they weren't sure if they were going to make it out but python?
And, the thing that I've also happy about just as a plug for the tool I'm very excited about is
encode here I'm notice that I'm running around inside of all of these...case and
I'm getting a nice the highlighting and the good stuff that I would expect to see
especially within the java one...languages...code, yeah,
it's pretty it's pretty ridiculous like it's not...it's got cool stuff ok there's a whole other talk.
Then I can go and make those calls.
This is just showing you what a web api that returns
swagger is but this isn't at this point at this moment this
actually isn't an ad her api app right because metadata
it matters and there's a piece of missing metadata here I will...
as your which humidity is right problem so I'm going to click as your api app sdk.
And, it's...grab a couple...new get packages and here is what I want to show you...this is important
I want you to understand there are no more black boxes anymore okay
to things just appeared api up dot jason.
The manifest for the app itself and then the api
...and fig measure resource in the deployment...go ahead and open up that api of jason...
...is another way...invest zooming out.
So, adorable when managers...
So, this api half.
...coding that's like using your...weird keyboard.
Dvorak with your problem.
This api app is telling as...itself.
Where that api definition is because there's nothing that says that has to be its last swagger
that's a convention but certainly if this were another app existing app...and app that I was adding stuff to
it might be somewhere else but also information like versioning that's important as well as the
...important because the api apps that we generate that run inside of asher
actually our new get packages so we take your api and we put
into a new get package within upload to asher and there's a couple
...reasons for...for doing this by putting it into a package let's say
scott builds a geo location api and he wants to share...your location api with other
customers inside of asher we're going to have a new get style gallery that you can go to and,
you'll find all these apis just like you can find new gets to build applications in
...forms of...raised...today now if you're building a client
...to talk to api you'll find in this
...gallery of apis the apis you want to use if you click one of them will
just automatically...the asher for-you so it's...will actually be installed
...your subscription and it will be running for-you?
Let's dig into that right there because I think that very point is subtle
but crucial when I first heard about api apps I was like okay so I'll make
an api and then I have the hosted and think about it I don't want to be a host...I
...as I like softwares a service...want to be the one doing the servicing I would like
to give it to you and have you hosted in your own thing remember how we
said that web sites became web apps and web apps run inside of your
hosting plan your hosting plan is the hidden virtual machine underneath that manages
your stuff what he's saying is when I say I'm going to get spots geo location api
and instance of that is created and brought into my world and
I own it and I control it and I decide when it gets updated you
manager I manage how much memory it gets...with the pricing is like if you
...israeli you scale yourself exacting teachers a web as and
...a new version comes out I decide whether or not I want to auto update for
...versions or take another one will...portal another,
another feature because it's a new get package is we have the ability to say my app
could automatically start taking advantage of new version so it's a new versions published ipod
...publishes a new version of...
Of his geo location api one if my applications configured to take audio updates what will
happen any minor updates will automatically go live in my production...me touching anything I'd have to go
and manage all these things which means as an organization you can
...api apps right across all the apps you're running inside
...organization and not have to have...go sit there and go push it to this and
...to this we will do all the heavy lifting for you so well, he unlocks that machine you can see that
I've got a slack connector any drop box connector I've also got twitter
connectors these are api apps that are running inside of my
posting plan this is not microsoft will handle drop box stuff for, you know,
this is you have an instance of this api up and that's really nice so...go and click on
the slack connector I've got to manage it and monitor it and deal with
it like any other application within my system and notice this
the click on api definition and I
...see that there's some swagger and as...knows about that so now I can post messages
into slack channels as an example okay so then if
we look at one that I published earlier I'm actually going to switch over
...as...cards that's ok with you actually before...jump into this one we go back
...real quick and show how we would publish design gis we just built that's a good point it's going
...close that scenario would hire...hitting a cancel...lot so
...well so after scott had
...api let's say you wanted to publish it up as an api app
...we right that's on the project complex publish there's a new thing that shows up in preview format
...click-through too fast we never saw...cancel sometimes sorry.
Sorry.
I apologize.
I need to just, you know, the thing is...actually...
So, you'll notice there's a new feature here microsoft as
your api apps shows appear right and then I would go in either pick them
...one or go and create a neuron here
okay and remember how you get ten free web same thing
applies you can go and make these for free and have fun and do the same things with either trial or your
free the subscription benefits as before but the point that he's making
...that you publish these and...treated the same except if they
are api apps proper they know other things they know things like...
api definition so this thing called asher cards that I wanted to bring up
is an interesting project and I believe I've got that running up here?
Right now so I'll show you what it is.
As your cards...have measure currents apologize.
It's grab that here we go and this is a brady guesstimate this is a card shuffle as I can say
new dec it makes a call back-to-back and shuffle the deck and then deals out the
cards and then you can see the answer deck of cards ok so there's swagger for
...the back-end service for this in this case is an angular app that's making
the call back okay so this is a static website api
it has swagger for.
What things you can do on the decked make a new decked shuffle it deal it how many cards in the decked
stuff like that ok I go into?
Go into the as your portal we can see that it knows about that
stuff okay so.
If we switch back over here radius been so kind as to make a consul client you seen the
consul client before less interesting let's introduce an into a
new concept here.
It's easy to make a little contact application that I
just made right and then say hey look I called...get yea but when things get
hard is when it's like okay now author to twitter and manage all of that token stuff and then
put in facebook and then suddenly my five line sample application becomes eight
hundred five lines where eight hundred lines of it manage the authentication and five
lines the actual...may reno of code in the room.
...fun in it so who wants to write when you when you ride a
...app who was to right the calls to the call back your eyes
into process them and all this kind of stuff the authentication code is a
concern that is orthogonal to the app itself it doesn't matter that the
card app those cards are the contact us context those are things should be handle
for-you so there's a gateway also owned by you this is an app is not a
...them...as you're thing this is a using gateways automatically...and it sits in front of
that application so I just called that out
...happily just work because it was public authenticated but I can go in
make a twitter account I did this area dev account...my secret
keys under identity here within the gateway and then
set-up twitter authentication or facebook or
microsoft or whatever for this particular machine and then call that as
an authenticated service so now I want to show that is...I can go in here...we
talk about auto updates I can go like this there's anonymous
there's authenticated there's also internal which is
it's public amongst people who are inside of your
as your resource group so that your apis can call each other but it's not accessible
the outside which is and actually you more useful than you would think because if you're going to use this on a workflow inside
of a logic app and think about those things are what they discover...well so you can see the
oddities the often beyond inherited by parents, yeah, so, this is really,
really significant so I can go back over here to my application that was going
and calling these and this part here create
cards make a new deck of cards that's those two lines of code and this is a fun
half and I did a car we...as a consul lap not to say this is
a best practice but just to take the concept of a consul lap and...do it...
Which I think is to insane to not do...run the consul
...and then promptly
authenticate with twitter which I think is epic just on principle?
And, then redirects me and then I get the decked id of that...
Grady is going to feel really good because it three in the
...like we have to authenticate against twitter and the...would do that that's insane.
But, it makes the point doesn't so then.
Our good friend brady goes and does the same thing four-h door app?
You go like this and you've seen this before right connect
into a service.
Now we have a much better application and I had deal and he's going
to go and bring those down and now that works so the authentication has
nothing to do with the api so now think about all the
apis you have your company that are useful that are interesting
...swagger put them up into as
your apps service and start taking those...cutting concerns and abstract them away
...clients can be used from mobile web consul.
It's hot so let's.
Shift gears a little bit...logic it and go logic and
...good call so we saw this.
Before this idea of this surface here
ok and it's a start logic...on the right-hand side here it says
is really important api apps in this resource
group this is my stuff this isn't all of the applications
that are available that's a whole other thing that we have the resource group on the start what.
Do I have a research group interpret?
I do know...browse.
You make me look for...have a lot of stuff so you research groups not
...research groups browse research groups so when you create api apps and
...create logic apps we ask you to put them in a resource group and
resource group is technically a container and the reason we want you put...a resource group
...it means you can actually manage them all is one instance so let's say I've got a web app that
...five api apps...app...well you reference all these things together
and what we call the resource group and the benefit there is if you want to...deleting and
...the resource group and all this stuff is goes away so mine happens to be is a good thing
...brought up because mine sitting in car dealer logic
...twenty-five total resources ic eleven api apps the gateway
the web app and then yesterday I...feel it was getting a little sluggish I've got
eleven different apis there and I get twenty five different things going on so I looked at the memory usage
...eighty five percent?
This is a great thing about the cloud you want the cloud to run hot you want to save money
is running a ten percent then...not really do any work what eighty five percent was a little
...for me and I just went and changed from small.
To medium should be a little bit nicer and I'll go and clean-up and remove some of the apps that
I don't want I control that so that's the example where I choose to live at
a platform as a service world I think about things that way but I'm not ignorant to
the fact that there is in fact virtual machines also that I control also the benefits of api app mobile
...web apps all running...the same container which you can basically drag sliders up and down to
...right auto scale.
All these features are right there and...so I clicked on the api
...in my resource group these are the ones that are connected including
my web api and just to make the point a node sample as well
that is a valid in legitimate api as well as things like slack connector and stuff like that and
twitter.
Psychological so I can actually click of the on here and go back to logic.
...where's my logic...create.
No.
The other portal is starting to grow on
me because it's like a whole operating system in html.
And, let's take a look here actually...I have a better one I'd like to use
choose...a...one from scratch sir I'm going off script I want to use this
one you're free to build one no...I...this one here which is awesome this one
here has a recurrence that then searches for tweet with the name handsome
...which is probably a dangerous thing to do?
Let's say build when.
...I do here.
Is angry at me?
Notice is authorized this action that's where I...the twitter that was allowed
...drop box connector here is taking the data that flows
from twitter and taking the body of those...a languages once...once and
...twitter...winter I can do it every five minutes or whatever you want to
every allow seconds that would be insane and, then there's a little language here and this is going this
apis it better the...portal actually updates a lot...talk about these things like body
array text pretext retreat count without out of this wire that's out of this wagner so the
reason that reasons wires important as...start building designers like this
...I assume the api apps that metadata is what's driving all of this letting
handsomemoreover if I click on that dot-dot-dot I get the entire thing including in this case
tweet id which I see is specifically like that tweet id okay then I'm going
to go and drop those things into drop aac so I'm actually.
Hit save on this one here come back out and enable this and I want to
wait an hour something to run it now.
And, then I can click on each individual run.
See what's running and what's not.
Within that.
Entire orchestrate workflow upload.
tweaks and we saved them to drop box and now they are here.
That's the tweet...I just use the tweet ideas the file.
Not cool.
Thanking a newports storm that's not good area there's a retreat for brought
...so that I could say well don't say
...so you might look at this and say well this is similar to something like, you know,
if this than that or something like that but
...marketplace let's look at the marketplaces it's quite a bit more another talking about
...logic apps and the api apps you...soon to do this we already
had this gallery talk about early before of like fifty of these things we've prebuilt a lot of these came
from this talk teams there's a lot of this talk connectors in here as well which is you connectors a lot of popular
sas services a lot of microsoft services...downhill
and this brings up another interesting point layers of abstraction how much you choose to
hide you can be thinking about this at the high-level business process like in the demo where I get
an order and I text someone with julio you can
do search twitter and put it in drop box and then again might remind you of things like
...a or but this is running on my machines like
...on my hardware even though I'm borrowing it from
asher other examples we've done is we've actually look at the sequel database and move data into something like dynamics
are sales force yep...records at a new custer
gets addison where we go instigate customer into our serum we've seen some really interesting things
people have taken old legacy apps really old ones
that they're afraid to touch let's say you've got a classic asp applet
...or database...all switched over to sales force but everyone likes
...works just fine I won't touch it you can go and have a job that runs and pull that out and sticks
into the new crm you can
attached things together now layers abstraction...twitter?
Ftp pop http.
Sf so you can choose the layer triangles let's do a really low-level one-paragraph with
...http so the http was interesting because in that case he's not going to have the metadata and stuff
...doing...go rise ik there's no api up here so I'm going to call out rate to a
...the added already know and what we more direct because?
Using that swagger help another medical concept think about we saw
that marketplace we're in preview today so we don't have this feature yet but another feature that's coming online
pretty soon is you might be saying hey I want to create my own api apps but I don't want them to show up in the as
...marketplace that would be crazy I don't want the world...see them we also have the ability
to have a marketplace for your organization so when you build your own api apps
...you upload them...upload into a place where anybody in your org can come
...find them in a marketplace just like that and choose and
...but just yours so we're going to make it really easy
...organizations to create their own apis host them and,
share them inside their own groups.
be get to a url I that has my blood sugar.
And, I can choose authentication or what I want to do and all those kinds of stuff that is a valid
...know that for a fact notes not at all no thank you for telling that and?
Reply doing
...because we don't have the swagger data I get access to the heterogeneous
...everything because there's...I could even go and
add another one and then go and either
...and post this to another orion I like this one called this based on
...scope and run scope is a really cool...not...microsoft thing somebody else they are
Basically...called soap scope back in the day it's a proxy
...in between you and your web service and
...you have buckets for debugging so I have a special magic bucket and I can
go and take that magic bucket and stick that here there's also known called request
been that is really nice and I can decide where the bodies...come from and I can pick that
body from here so you pulling up...the output of the previous by them.
So, I'm going to get from here and...there.
And, let's see if it if it works that'd be kinda cool...
I'm not surprised at all moi.
My blood sugar is sixteen-node.
...getting...now you're quick poured that...that would do nothing has also you need
...regular pepsi no so here we've thrown that through so when I was doing
debugging and stuff of the twitter and drop
box just popped in a request been or run scope and I figure those things
...get to watch them now that authentication thing...about how
authentication flow through something like this is hired plugging real api absent.
What part of...talk about...if you put like twitter up there...to...yeah, so,
if we go and look at a more interesting are complicated api
logic app rather let's take a look at one of those and logic
...that has a lot of different bits of authorization you don't want
to have to think about like I log the user in and now I want to flow off through
an entire call a series of calls?
Especially logic...that's where you really don't have any where would you put your
...all this...what you do.
Each instance is authenticated
...and sitting in an...app right like this one.
We've got sequel and sales force and truly of an
I dropped in twitter to do something at the end.
Twitter says connecting to api app and then depending on...I've authenticated this
one again or not it will say authorize so I say individually
authorized that instance
two-run on my behalf and just like any other app in twitter or any of
the other things that you might co-author against you can revoke that potentially you can set that
at the logic at level or at the api itself or what I could've done
...could have also gone increase thetwitter connector manually, yeah,
from the plus the very bottom of the marketplace and,
...drills in the properties of the twitter will actually have places where your api
keys and your authorization key goes right to do that as well so you might do
that case you might want to have a...a twitter connector sitting out there one
that's on behalf of view and you might want to have another one that's on behalf of your company and what's even cooler
as you can actually create both of those and with some of the features inside of asher we have
our back...base access I can basically say scott's allowed to
tweet on behalf of the company right and everybody else is not...that between on behalf the
company now and then one thing that I want to add because this is just the thing that I'm on right now that...really think
is important is there's a lot of push towards raising the layers of abstraction and making
...I grew up here floating in this logic app world but the reality is something doesn't work out you
want to figure it out ok so in this example here we actually have a fortunate thing...
error occurred and here it's saying you can't fetch
this swagger api so that one individual logic abbas told me that there's a problem maybe
that's disabled or maybe I haven't figure that out because these applications
are still our apps they are web...underneath...all...
okay I can come in here and I can look at what who's hosting that particular
thing here she by the way I told you I switched to medium who's hosting that and now look at this
I can go in see are there any errors what's going on these
are deployed with get or whatever I can even I love this by
the way this is just really makes the point about high-level versus low-level
I'm inside the asher portal something's gone wrong here no
...work...put it back again know what
happens let's get in there now I'm a tiny fake
...prompt?
In the cloud that's awesome thank you...we are
...the trying to figure out front so I can even click on processes.
In this api app take a look at this see
the node at click on the node at from that how much
memories using is their problem...the process so when we're
up what modules that have loaded in memory for crying out loud.
What version is it?
People show you platform as a service solutions and they say you just deploy
...works but when it doesn't
...figure it out and that's why I think is so powerful about what they're doing here because they didn't go
and create...service and then hide all the
complexity the abstracted away but I've got a great
deb ops dashboard with all sorts of detail if I want to look at from a business
person's perspective how many instances how hard they working at it out but now I
can go all the way down to a specific thing and say that's the wrong version of that deal.
We're going to go into but...goes even further than that if...national studio you can actually attached to remote
debug are the same running instance in the cloud as well so nothing prevents you from
going to bs it's in...server explore.
And, api...show up as a first-class...a...
You know, it's going to ask...you talk about that...I login
...and inside the server explore we're going to show you all of your mobile apps
all your web apps all of your api apps and you can drill in
...look at the logs if you will see streaming logs from
...api apps logic apps web apps...running in the cloud you can do it right from inside
a visual studio you can also write click on these things as well and they'll be in
...and you can live debug in the cloud it takes about thirty seconds to
...the very first-time is we install the remote...in your
...environment's nowonce it's done you can just do it.
Is finally showing what streaming logs?
Attaching...so that streaming log stuff that does prompt stuff I saw you can see it in
here and what makes me happy about this actually funny story is not only can I
do it in the portal not only can do it in visual studio right but if I want
to go out to the command-line and type as your site log
tail foo-foo and then I'm using the cross-platform
...and I can actually go in debug these things as well I did that recently
seeing some logs as it was being deployed we might do this if you using a visual
...code on a non windows device absolutely so I think that's our time?
We have been the lesser scott's we're really sincerely excited about
asher application service and we hope that you check it out as well thank you very much.